Guide to the Records of the Library of Arabic Literature: Fellow Interviews AD.RG.024.003.001
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
Library of Arabic Literature: Fellow Interviews
2019-01-13-2019-12-10
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
AD.RG.024.003.001
17.7 Gigabytes
58.41 Gigabytes
Biographical / Historical
A program sponsored by the NYU Abu Dhabi Institute and funded by Tamkeen, the Library of Arabic Literature makes available Arabic editions and English translations of significant works of Arabic literature, with an emphasis on the seventh to nineteenth centuries.
Books in the series are edited and translated by internationally recognized scholars. They are published in parallel-text and English-only editions in both print and electronic formats. PDFs of Arabic editions are available for free download. The Library of Arabic Literature also publishes distinct scholarly editions with critical apparatus and a separate Arabic-only series aimed at young readers.
The program's ultimate goal is to introduce Arabic's rich literary heritage to a general audience of readers as well as to scholars and students.
Reference and for more information: libraryofarabicliterature.org
Scope and Contents
Library of Arabic Literature: Fellow Interviews is a collection of video-recorded interviews with scholars awarded fellowships to contribute to the Library of Arabic Literature (LAL) publications. This particular collection of interviews were recorded between January and December of 2019, and includes six interviewees: Bilal Orfall, Mohammed Rustom, Maurice Pomerantz, Marcel Kurpershoek, Joseph Lowry and Julia Bray. Each interview session inclues a full interview, and a longer and shorter edited version prepared for social media. Some interview sessions were recorded separately, in Arabic and English.
Interviewees discuss the titles and texts they have worked on as part of their Fellowship with LAL. Most of the interviews are conducted by LAL Fellow and Editorial Board member Bilal Orfall.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in six series by interview session, and chronologically in the order of when the sessions took place.
Existence and Location of Copies
Copies of these recordings are available on the Library of Arabic Literature Soundcloud and YouTube channels.
https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCwV-2Tqtsl7iTJK2cy7YwiQ
https://soundcloud.com/lal_nyuad
Existence and Location of Originals
Original, preservation quality recordings are preserved in the NYUAD Library Digital Preservation Repository.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The videos were coordinated and produced by the Library of Arabic Literature program office and filmed by NYUAD Library, for eventual preservation as part of the NYUAD University Archives.
- Interview Session with Bilal Orfall and Mohammed Rustom, 2019-01-13; adrg024-003_01; 3.24 Gigabytes
  Scope and Contents
  Library of Arabic Literature Senior Fellow Mohammed Rustom talks to Library of Arabic Literature Senior Fellow BiLibrary of Arabic Literature Orfali at NYUAD about the texts Orfali is working on for Library of Arabic Literature, including al-Tawhidi and Miskawayh's al-Hawamil wal-shawamil (The Philosopher Responds) and al-Nisaburi's 'Uqala' al-majanin (Wise Madmen).
  Interview recorded in the NYUAD Archives and Special Collections Reading Room by CDS Digital Specialist Rebecca Pittam.
  - Bilal Orfali_Of Anecdotes and Wise Fools_Arabic (20:27), adrg024-003_01_1; 1.69 Gigabytes; 20:27 total_running_time (Box E-records, Folder CDS-ASC)
  - Bilal Orfali_Of Anecdotes and Wise Fools_Arabic_Social Media (02:02), adrg024-003_01_2; 1553 Megabytes
  - Bilal Orfali_Of Anecdotes and Wise Fools_English (13:55), adrg024-003_01_3; 1.16 Gigabytes
  - Bilal Orfali_Of Anecdotes and Wise Fools_English_Socail Media 1 (00:52), adrg024-003_01_4; 51.3 Megabytes
  - Bilal Orfali_Of Anecdotes and Wise Fools_English_Socail Media 2 (02:16), adrg024-003_01_5; 173.8 Megabytes
- Interview Session with Mohammed Rustom and Bilal Orfall, 2019-01-13; adrg024-003_02; 2.81 Gigabytes
  Library of Arabic Literature Senior Fellow Bilal Orfali talks to Library of Arabic Literature Senior Fellow Mohammed Rustom at NYUAD about the text Rustom is working on for Library of Arabic Literature, a book on the nature of God by the 6th/12th-century mystic and philosopher, 'Ayn al-Qudat
  - Mohammed Rustom_Ayn al-Qudat's Quintessence of Reality and its Importance Today_Arabic (14:45), adrg024-003_02_1; 1.26 Gigabytes
  - Mohammed Rustom_Ayn al-Qudat's Quintessence of Reality and its Importance Today_English (14:44), adrg024-003_02_2; 1.2 Gigabytes
  - Mohammed Rustom_Ayn al-Qudat's Quintessence of Reality and its Importance Today_English_Social Media 1 (01:16), adrg024-003_02_3; 88.2 Megabytes
  - Mohammed Rustom_Ayn al-Qudat's Quintessence of Reality and its Importance Today_English_Social Media 2 (03:18), adrg024-003_02_4; 270.8 Megabytes
- Interview Session with Maurice Pomerantz and Bilal Orfall, 2019-05-12; adrg024-003_03; 3.93 Gigabytes
  Library of Arabic Literature editor-translator and 2019 Senior Library of Arabic Literature Fellow Bilal Orfali interviews Library of Arabic Literature Editor Maurice Pomerantz about his work with the series, including A Hundred and One Nights, The Philosopher Responds, and other upcoming projects.
  - Maurice Pomerantz_The Magic of Words_Arabic (18:14), adrg024-003_03_1; 1.63 Gigabytes
  - Maurice Pomerantz_Collaboration and Translation_Arabic_Social Media (02:10), adrg024-003_03_2; 171.7 Megabytes
  - Maurice Pomerantz_The Magic of Words_English (19:24), adrg024-003_03-3; 1.74 Gigabytes
  - Maurice Pomerantz_Collaboration and Translation_English_Social Media 1 (00:51), adrg024-003_04_4; 52.5 Megabytes
  - Maurice Pomerantz_Collaboration and Translation_English_Social Media 2 (01:54), adrg024-003_04_5; 149.9 Megabytes
  - Maurice Pomerantz_Collaboration and Translation_English_Social Media 1&2 (02:23), adrg024-003_04_6; 195.1 Megabytes
- Interview Session with Marcel Kurpershoek and Bilal Orfall, 2019-05-12; adrg024-003_04; 3.8 Gigabytes
  Library of Arabic Literature editor-translator and 2019 Senior Library of Arabic Literature Fellow Bilal Orfali interviews Senior Library of Arabic Literature Fellow Marcel Kurpershoek about his work with the series, including his published Library of Arabic Literature edition-translations: Arabian Satire by Hmedan al-Shwe'ir and Arabian Romantic by Ibn Sbayyil.
  - Marcel Kurpershoek_Nabati and Classical Poetry_Arabic (19:56), adrg024-003_04-1; 1.74 Gigabytes
- Interview Session with Joseph Lowry and Bilal Orfall, 2019-12-10; adrg024-003_05
  Senior Library of Arabic Literature Fellow BiLal Orfali interviews Senior Library of Arabic Literature Fellow Joseph Lowry about his work with the series, including his published edition-translation, The Epistle on Legal Theory by al-Shāfiʿī, and his current project, an edition-translation of Ibn Qutaybah's Taʾwīl mukhtalif al-ḥadīth.
- Interview Session with Julia Bray and Bilal Orfall, 2019-12-10; adrg024-003_06
  Senior Library of Arabic Literature Fellow Bilal Orfali interviews Library of Arabic Literature editor-translator Julia Bray about al-Tanūkhī's al-Faraj baʿd al-shiddah and her recently-published Library of Arabic Literature edition-translation of its first volume, Stories of Piety and Prayer: Deliverance Follows Adversity.